https://www.backcountrygear.com/privacy-policy-cookie-restriction-mode/

This website requires cookies to provide all of its features. For more information on what data is contained in the cookies, please see our
Privacy Policy page. To accept cookies from this site, please click the Allow button below.Allow
Menu Camp and HikeBackpacksBackpacking PacksUltralight PacksClimbing PacksSki & Snowboard PacksDaypacksHydration PacksKid's PacksExternal Frame PacksChild CarriersDog PacksCourier & Shoulder BagsLumbar PacksDuffels & TotesTravel PacksDry Packs & BagsPack AccessoriesRunning Packs & AccessoriesTents3 Season Tents4 Season TentsFamily Camping TentsUltralight TentsBiviesTarps & WingsBug SheltersHammocksTent AccessoriesTent FootprintsSleeping BagsDown Sleeping BagsSynthetic Sleeping BagsCar Camping BagsComforters & QuiltsBag LinersSleeping Bag AccessoriesSleeping PadsSelf InflatingAir PadsClosed Cell PadsAccessoriesTravel & Camping PillowsChair Kits & SeatingCotsHydrationWater TreatmentTreatment AccessoriesWater HaulersWater BottlesWater BladdersHydration PacksAccessoriesKitchenCamp Stoves & GrillsCanister StovesLiquid Fuel StovesAlcohol & Wood StovesCookwareTitanium CookwarePlates & DishesCups & MugsUtensilsWater TreatmentBackpacking MealsOrganic FoodEnergy FoodBeer & SpiritsCoffee & TeaBear CanistersStove Parts & AccessoriesKitchen AccessoriesCoolersTablesTrekking PolesTrekking PolesStaffsAccessoriesLightingHeadlampsLanternsFlashlightsAccessoriesElectronics & OpticsPower SourcesAvalanche BeaconsWatchesCompassesOpticsDog GearDog Packs & HarnessesDog Leashes & CollarsDog Toys & TreatsDog AccessoriesDog Coats & BootiesDog FlotationAccessoriesBear ProtectionBooksBug Nets & RepellentCamp ChairsCompression SacksDry BagsEmergency GearFirst AidHammocks & AccessoriesKnives and ToolsLighters & FirestartersPersonal CarePower SuppliesRepair KitsStickers and PatchesStorage BagsStuff SacksTablesTent StakesToiletriesOutdoor BlanketsTreatments and CleanersUmbrellasWater Tight CasesOutdoor RecreationGames & ToysKitesFishing GearSlacklinesClimbingRopes & CordageDynamic RopeStatic RopeCordageRope AccessoriesProtection & HardwareActive Pro - CamsPassive Pro - NutsAscendersCrash PadsPulleys & SwivelsBelay & Rappel DevicesBolts & HangersRigging PlatesIce & Snow ProtectionPitons, Hooks & Aid ProCarabiners & QuickdrawsNon-Locking CarabinersLocking CarabinersQuickdrawsSlings & WebbingDaisy Chains & TethersSlings & RunnersWebbingClimbing ShoesShoes - Women'sShoes - Men's & UnisexHarnessesMen's & Unisex HarnessesWomen's HarnessesYouth HarnessesHelmetsClimbing Packs & BagsRope BagsHaul BagsClimbing PacksSummit PacksGear DufflesIce and SnowIce Axes & ToolsIce Axe AccessoriesCramponsProtectionBig WallAid ProAscendersBolting GearHarnessesHaul BagsAiders and DaisiesPulleys & SwivelsShelters & LedgesAccessoriesRescue & IndustrialCarabinersHarnessesStatic RopePulleys & SwivelsRigging PlatesAscenders & DescendersSlings & AidersClimbing AccessoriesChalk Bags & ChalkBoulderingTraining, Holds, & Skin CareAccessory CarabinersClimbing & Belay GlovesClimbing GuidesTravelWheeled LuggageTravel Packs & BagsLarge Travel PacksTravel DaypacksDuffelsLaptop Packs & BagsShoulder & Messenger BagsTravel TotesPhotographyPhotography AccessoriesElectronicsSolar & Portable PowerProtective CasesOrganizersCubes & OrganizersToiletry KitsPersonal CareFirst AidSkin CareTravel TowelsWater TreatmentTravel AccessoriesSleep LinersPillowsWallets and Money ClipsTravel SecurityInsect ProtectionTravel ApparelMen's TopsMen's BottomsWomen's TopsWomen's BottomsClothing AccessoriesSnow SportsSki & Snowboard PacksSnowshoesMen's SnowshoesWomen's SnowshoesSnowshoe PolesSnowshoe AccessoriesHats, Gloves & GaitersMen's HatsMen's Mitts & GlovesWomen's HatsWomen's Mitts & GlovesGaitersGogglesAvalanche GearBeaconsProbesAvalanche-Ready PacksSnow Shovels & SawsSkinsSki PolesAccessoriesTraction DevicesSnow Sports BooksSnowsports ApparelMen's Snowsports ApparelWomen's Snowsports ApparelPaddle SportsPaddle Apparel - Men'sPaddle Apparel - Women'sFootwearPFDsDry StorageCook, Camp, & LoungeBoat AccessoriesRescue & SafetyMenMen's JacketsDown JacketsSynthetic-Filled JacketsSnowsports JacketsTechnical ShellsSoft ShellsWind JacketsFleece JacketsRain JacketsVestsMen's BottomsPant ShellsRain PantsWind PantsInsulated PantsHiking & Climbing PantsCasual Pants & JeansShortsMerino LeggingsSynthetic LeggingsSnowsports PantsMen's ShirtsCasual ShirtsSweaters & HoodiesSun-Protective ShirtsMerino & Bamboo TopsSynthetic TopsBaselayers & UnderwearBoxers and BriefsMerino & Bamboo TopsMerino BottomsSynthetic TopsSynthetic BottomsMen's HeadwearCapsBeaniesBalaclavasNeck and Ear WarmersSun ProtectionRain HatsGlovesLinersTechnical MittsTechnical GlovesCasual GlovesSocksRunning SocksSki SocksHiking SocksCold Weather SocksCasual SocksFootwearSandalsCasual ShoesApproach ShoesMountaineeringHiking & BackpackingTrail RunningBooties & SlippersClothing AccessoriesBandanasGaitersEyewearBug NettingBelts & WalletsWomenWomen's JacketsDown JacketsSynthetic-Filled JacketsSnowsports JacketsTechnical ShellsSoft ShellsFleece JacketsWind JacketsRain JacketsVestsWomen's BottomsPant ShellsRain PantsSnowsports PantsInsulated PantsCasual Pants & JeansShorts, Skirts & DressesHiking & Climbing PantsMerino LeggingsSynthetic LeggingsWomen's ShirtsCasual ShirtsSweaters & HoodiesMerino & Bamboo TopsSynthetic TopsSun ShirtsBaselayers & UnderwearBras and UnderwearMerino & Bamboo TopsMerino BottomsSynthetic TopsSynthetic BottomsHeadwearCapsBeaniesBalaclavasNeck and Ear WarmersSun ProtectionRain HatsGlovesLinersTechnical MittsTechnical GlovesCasual GlovesSocksRunning SocksSki SocksHiking SocksCold Weather SocksCasual SocksFootwearSandalsCasual Shoes & BootsApproach ShoesMountaineeringHiking & BackpackingTrail RunningBooties & SlippersClothing AccessoriesBandanasGaitersEyewearBug NettingBelts & WalletsFootwearMen's CasualCasual ShoesSandalsBooties & SlippersMen's ClimbingApproach ShoesClimbing ShoesMen's Trail & MountainTrail Running ShoesHiking & BackpackingMountaineering BootsWomen's CasualCasual ShoesSandalsBooties & SlippersWomen's ClimbingApproach ShoesClimbing ShoesWomen's Trail & MountainTrail Running ShoesHiking & BackpackingMountaineering BootsAccessoriesFootbedsTraction DevicesCleaners and TreatmentsBrandsAll BrandsTop BrandsArc'teryxBig AgnesBlack DiamondDMMEdelridExpedFive TenGarmontGranite GearHillebergHydro FlaskLa SportivaMammutMarmotMetoliusMountain HardwearMountainsmithMSRMystery RanchNEMONRSOspreyOutdoor ResearchPatagoniaPetzlRabSea to SummitScarpaSmartWoolSnow PeakThe North FaceTherm-a-RestWestern MountaineeringWild CountryClearanceBackpacksTentsSleeping BagsMen's ApparelMen's JacketsMen's BottomsMen's ShirtsBaselayers & UnderwearAccessoriesSocksWomen's ApparelWomen's JacketsWomen's BottomsWomen's ShirtsBaselayer & UnderwearAccessoriesSocksClimbingFootwearMen's FootwearWomen's FootwearCamping And Hiking AccessoriesSnowsports EquipmentPaddle GearTravelSaleBackpack SaleBackpacking PacksDaypacks & CouriersTravel Packs & LuggageOther PacksPack AccessoriesTent SaleSleeping Bag SaleMen's Apparel SaleJacket SaleBottoms SaleCasual Wear SaleBaselayer SaleAccessories SaleWomen's Apparel SaleJacket SaleBottoms SaleCasual Wear SaleBaselayer SaleAccessories SaleClimbing SaleCarabiners & QuickdrawsProtection & HardwareHelmets, Harnesses, & ShoesIce & Snow GearRopes, Webbing, & Sewn GoodsClimbing Accessories & OtherFootwear SaleMen's Footwear SaleWomen's Footwear SaleCamping Accessories SaleSleeping PadsLighting & ElectronicsHydrationSacks & BagsOther AccessoriesBackcountry Kitchen SaleStovesCookwareDishes & UtensilsFoodKitchen AccessoriesSnowsports SaleSnowsports EquipmentSnowsports ApparelPaddle Gear SaleTravel Sale12 Days of SavingsGift CenterGifts For HimGifts For HerStaff FavoritesDamn Nice GiftsStocking StuffersGifts for BackpackersGifts for Car CampersGifts for HikersGifts for ClimbersGifts for Skiers & BoardersGifts for PaddlersGifts Under $50Gifts $50 to $100Gifts Over $100
Account
Home
Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
This privacy policy sets out how Backcountry Gear uses and protects any information that you give Backcountry Gear when you use this website. Backcountry Gear is committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement. Backcountry Gear may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes.
What we collect
We may collect the following information:
name
contact information including email address
demographic information such as postcode, preferences and interests
other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers
For the exhaustive list of cookies we collect see the List of cookies we collect section.
What we do with the information we gather
We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:
Internal record keeping.
We may use the information to improve our products and services.
We may periodically send promotional emails about new products, special offers or other information which we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.
From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research purposes. We may contact you by email, phone, fax or mail. We may use the information to customise the website according to your interests.
Security
We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online.
How we use cookies
A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer's hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.
We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.
Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us. You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.
Links to other websites
Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.
Controlling your personal information
You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following ways:
whenever you are asked to fill in a form on the website, look for the box that you can click to indicate that you do not want the information to be used by anybody for direct marketing purposes
if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by writing to or emailing us at bcgeartech@backcountrygear.com
We will not sell, distribute or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.
You may request details of personal information which we hold about you under the Data Protection Act 1998. A small fee will be payable. If you would like a copy of the information held on you please write to .
If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please write to or email us as soon as possible, at the above address. We will promptly correct any information found to be incorrect.
List of cookies we collect
The table below lists the cookies we collect and what information they store.
COOKIE nameCOOKIE Description
CART
The association with your shopping cart.
CATEGORY_INFO
Stores the category info on the page, that allows to display pages more quickly.
COMPARE
The items that you have in the Compare Products list.
CURRENCY
Your preferred currency
CUSTOMER
An encrypted version of your customer id with the store.
CUSTOMER_AUTH
An indicator if you are currently logged into the store.
CUSTOMER_INFO
An encrypted version of the customer group you belong to.
CUSTOMER_SEGMENT_IDS
Stores the Customer Segment ID
EXTERNAL_NO_CACHE
A flag, which indicates whether caching is disabled or not.
FRONTEND
You sesssion ID on the server.
GUEST-VIEW
Allows guests to edit their orders.
LAST_CATEGORY
The last category you visited.
LAST_PRODUCT
The most recent product you have viewed.
NEWMESSAGE
Indicates whether a new message has been received.
NO_CACHE
Indicates whether it is allowed to use cache.
PERSISTENT_SHOPPING_CART
A link to information about your cart and viewing history if you have asked the site.
POLL
The ID of any polls you have recently voted in.
POLLN
Information on what polls you have voted on.
RECENTLYCOMPARED
The items that you have recently compared.
STF
Information on products you have emailed to friends.
STORE
The store view or language you have selected.
USER_ALLOWED_SAVE_COOKIE
Indicates whether a customer allowed to use cookies.
VIEWED_PRODUCT_IDS
The products that you have recently viewed.
WISHLIST
An encrypted list of products added to your Wishlist.
WISHLIST_CNT
The number of items in your Wishlist.
About Us
The BCG Story
Read Our Blog
Eugene Retail Store
Local Events
Privacy Policy
Terms of Use
Payment Methods
Promotion Policy
Return Policy
Shipping Cost
International Orders
Shop by Category Camp and Hike +
Backpacks Tents Sleeping Bags Sleeping Pads Hydration Kitchen Trekking Poles Lighting Electronics & Optics Dog Gear Accessories Outdoor Recreation
Climbing +
Ropes & Cordage Protection & Hardware Carabiners & Quickdraws Slings & Webbing Climbing Shoes Harnesses Helmets Climbing Packs & Bags Ice and Snow Big Wall Rescue & Industrial Climbing Accessories
Travel +
Wheeled Luggage Travel Packs & Bags Photography Electronics Organizers Personal Care Water Treatment Travel Accessories Travel Apparel
Snow Sports +
Ski & Snowboard Packs Snowshoes Hats, Gloves & Gaiters Goggles Avalanche Gear Skins Ski Poles Accessories Traction Devices Snow Sports Books Snowsports Apparel
Paddle Sports +
Paddle Apparel - Men's Paddle Apparel - Women's Footwear PFDs Dry Storage Cook, Camp, & Lounge Boat Accessories Rescue & Safety
Men +
Men's Jackets Men's Bottoms Men's Shirts Baselayers & Underwear Men's Headwear Gloves Socks Footwear Clothing Accessories
Women +
Women's Jackets Women's Bottoms Women's Shirts Baselayers & Underwear Headwear Gloves Socks Footwear Clothing Accessories
Footwear +
Men's Casual Men's Climbing Men's Trail & Mountain Women's Casual Women's Climbing Women's Trail & Mountain Accessories
Top Brands +
Arc'teryx Big Agnes Black Diamond DMM Edelrid Exped Five Ten Garmont Granite Gear Hilleberg Hydro Flask La Sportiva Mammut Marmot Metolius Mountain Hardwear Mountainsmith MSR Mystery Ranch NEMO NRS Osprey Outdoor Research Patagonia Petzl Rab Sea to Summit Scarpa SmartWool Snow Peak The North Face Therm-a-Rest Western Mountaineering Wild Country
Clearance +
Backpacks Tents Sleeping Bags Men's Apparel Women's Apparel Climbing Footwear Camping And Hiking Accessories Snowsports Equipment Paddle Gear Travel
Sale +
Backpack Sale Tent Sale Sleeping Bag Sale Men's Apparel Sale Women's Apparel Sale Climbing Sale Footwear Sale Camping Accessories Sale Backcountry Kitchen Sale Snowsports Sale Paddle Gear Sale Travel Sale 12 Days of Savings
Staff Picks +
Stay at Home Gear Day Hiking Gear
Gift Center +
Gifts For Him Gifts For Her Staff Favorites Damn Nice Gifts Stocking Stuffers Gifts for Backpackers Gifts for Car Campers Gifts for Hikers Gifts for Climbers Gifts for Skiers & Boarders Gifts for Paddlers Gifts Under $50 Gifts $50 to $100 Gifts Over $100
Loading...
